<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Neo-Iskra</title>
    <link>https://iskra.money/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Neo-Iskra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iskra.money/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s What Happened Around Us</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/its_what_happened_around_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/its_what_happened_around_us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s hardly a need for an introduction paragraph. I could post some stock art of a pirate flag and you’d know what spurred this, assuming you haven’t just woken up from a years long coma and resisted the overpowering and righteous urge to hurl yourself through a window. The circus surrounding Johnny “Rape Her Corpse to Make Sure She’s Dead” Depp’s defamation trial aganist Amber Heard has been like asphixiation by helium, its certainly a bad thing no one seems to be handling well but a few people made funny noises because of it so most of us seem fine with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen quite a lot about how many outlets spent gross amounts of money to drag Amber Heard through the mud. Depp’s anecdote about Heard shitting the bed got more coverage than his previously mentioned admitted desire to rape Heard’s corpse and every half witted response his lawyer managed to squeak out between shoveling handfuls of shit into her gob was treated like the most well played legal strategy since OJ made his hands swell. Its a scene we’ve seen whenever the world is asked to examine the gross reality of violence against women, in fact tactical use of apologia we saw in this trial has already inspired the sludge of the Earth to copy Depp’s tactics in case of their own coming under fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not particularly interested in going into the media side of things however, Rayne Fisher-Quann has already done this in spectuaclar fashion, rather I want to look at the other side and talk about why the public is so eager to gobble up such slander. It would be easy to just say “Dumb dumb can’t think for self” and give myself a congratulatory wank, it would also be easy to tip toe around the heart of the matter and make this another episode of Men Bad: Tonight but neither approach offers anything of value or intrest to me (aside from the wank, of course) or you, seeing as how thats the same think piece we read about Kavanaugh and Spacey and Trump and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is not to paint Heard as a feminist icon or Joan of Arc, I’ll point to Fisher-Quann’s piece again with this excerpt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; I find no value in flattening the experiences or motivations of either party in this case to fit an easily consumable Marvel movie plotline. I’m not interested in buying into the dominant narrative that treats this trial like a soap opera, with characters that exist to be rooted for and against. Much of the popular discourse acts as though there are only two feasible options when it comes to Heard’s (and, really, any woman’s) innocence: either she’s an evil, psychotic manipulator who’s guilty on all counts, or she must have to be a perfectly innocent angel who’s never done anything wrong. I don’t think Amber Heard is a feminist hero, and I’m not saying this to make my support of her more palatable or to perform impartiality — I’m saying it because she shouldn’t have to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only men get to be complicated in the public eye. We can go round and round on if the latest abortion clinic bomber was really a bad guy or just misunderstood and we can certainly have a sit down conversation on how at fault a man is for the rape of a young woman in a frat house, and you can make quite a killing with a morally grey retelling of Jerffry Dahmer’s crimes, but women will either be all or nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can remember the confirmation hearing for Brett Kavanaugh you certainly remember the rape accusations. Everyone with a connection to the outside world had a front row seat to a future supreme court justice getting emotional over calendars and a parade of talking heads discussing if the women accusing Kavanaugh were telling the truth or secretly eating babies when the cameras weren’t pointed at them. More recently, Elon Musk’s defense that anyone who accused him of sexual assasult should be able to rattle off a road map of each fold and flap on his skin. While both the Kavanaugh camp and Musk’s comment were condemned by many they were defended by at least an equal amount. In fact, there seems to be little need to defend them in the media at this point. Ever since some genius said “What if the lady lied though” we’ve gained a never ending parade of online sleuths to instantly fire blindly at any case where a woman threatens a powerful man. This leads me to my central point: Society has never really had an issue with violence against women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly we like to have a pageant about the thing. I think an apt example is the case of the Exonerated Five, a group of black and latino men accused of violating a jogger in Central Park and jailed on extremely, extremely poor evidence. If you do any reading on this case you’ll find the woman at the center of it, Trisha Meili, is often cast to the side for a focus on racism and injustice in the NYPD. This is not because of some non-existant rivalry between POC and feminist historians but because even at the time of the case she was more a side detail to her own attack. The main feature was that POC were once again tasked to prove they aren’t walking around with boners set to automatically fire on white women. Compare this to white-on-white sex crimes of the day and you find no similar circus. The problem wasn’t that a woman had been raped, the problem was racial etiquette wasn’t upheld. Similarly no one seemed to particularly care about if Heard had been abused or not, I’ve even met people who had no idea that was a central part of the case, but rather if Depp had ever said a naughty word or two. This is what I mean by “society has never really had an issue with violence against women” because we always seem to find a way to shove it out of the way for preferred topics. A rape in a night club will be met with the ghoulish gas explusions questioning what she was wearing, how drunk was she, what was the percise word choice and tone, if her body had at any point released even a molecule of the “lets fuck” phermone that sent the man into a blind frenzy, etc. This even occurs in cases around extremely young victims as any search into your local high school or catholic church’s history will show. But if a rape occurs and the case has even one interesting quality to the vultures who run things such as a minority attacker, relevancy to a hot button issue, or the victim being of high status (the only quality I can think of that takes the victim into account) then we may give her the benefit of the account. I can’t even really call it something similar to the whore/madonna complex, its more like a whore/possible whore in tragic circumstances complex. Its not what happened to us, its what happened around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my stand up, I had a joke about the phrase “consent is sexy.” Essentially, I find it humorous in the most macabre way that we have to make fun sayings and phrases to remind people not to rape. Usually I pair it with things of a similar nature like “I before E except after C” or “Please excuse my dear aunt Sally” to emphasize the juvenile sexuality women have to fight against daily by breaking it down to the most simple level, our own trauma not being empathetic unless it sounds like Dr. Seuss wrote it. I’ve since retired the joke because it depresses me and this is precisely why, it’s not just how we talk about violence but how we don’t talk about it that follows this pattern. It isn’t enough that a human being has been beaten, raped, and left to die, we need to be able to pick out a greater narrative from it. After all, women are harmed all the time, that’s just life, come back when you’ve got something I’ll change the channel to hear about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freud’s Jokes and Their Relation to the Unconscious asserts that the enjoyment of humor comes from its relation to suppression of serious talk. In order for a joke to work you have to overcome any inhibitions around the topic of the humor and then allow themself to laugh at the humor derived from the topic. For example, if someone laughs at a rape joke you can fairly accurately infer their distaste for rape comes from a societal teaching and not any personal moral ground. Now with that in mind, look at the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iskra.money/ox-hugo/amberheardtweet.jpeg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any laughs that could be had from this tweet hinge on the viewer finding the appearance of a woman reliving immense trauma for a televised audience to be hilariously bad acting, to view a tale of domestic abuse the way a group of friends would view Manos: The Hands of Fate. Now consider the fact that this tweet and many similar tweets, memes, and videos went viral because of how many people saw a woman recounting true horror and lost themselves giggling. A popular saying online is that you can’t force a meme, that you can’t make something a popular image or joke without it naturally gaining that statue. No one had to force the now meme status of Heard’s case, we had already accepted that a woman’s trauma was entertainment first and tragedy second.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinoza and the Case of Endeavouring</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/spinoza_and_the_case_of_endeavouring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/spinoza_and_the_case_of_endeavouring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spinoza lays out in part 1 of ‘The Ethics’ that we are of one substance (God/nature) (1DVI). The substance then has infinite attributes, and modes upon which we are created. In this essay it will be shown what the account of endeavour is, how it relates to Adequate and Inadequate causes and finally how emotions play into both Endeavour and cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The account of Endeavour for Spinoza beings in Part Three of the Ethics, ‘Each thing, in so far as it is in itself, endeavours to persevere in its being.’ (3PVI). It is made clear that a being will oppose anything that will negate it and welcome anything that affirms it. Spinoza later goes on to claim in (3PVIII) that it is only External things that can kill us, but that we endeavour infinitely and when death does occur our substance is then transformed which endeavours also (if it is a being in itself). So, if there was no external world we would live forever. This however is absurd and thus we must die but it does mean that we cannot kill ourselves or our body (3PX). With this all together we can get a clear sense of what endeavouring is, the process upon which we seek to live forever (3PVIII). This is due to the idea that we are modifications of God&amp;rsquo;s substance and the idea that we have no free will but that everything must occur out of necessity (1PXXXIII) (2PXLIX). This said, then, its apparent that humans have no free will but rather it comes from the necessary and nothing could come out of that necessary, for if you did something of your free will that could mean that there exists something outside God which is absurd (1DVI). Therefore, it is important to examine then what is the difference between why a person is able to have less or more ‘power’, which is to say reality and the knowledge of our reality. Even though all humans Endeavour it be examined what is the connection between our Endeavouring and increasing or decreasing our power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comes through the form and Adequate and Inadequate causes. The former being that of which we can understand the cause of the effect (2DIV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;By an adequate idea, I mean an idea which, in so far as it is considered in itself, without relation to the object, has all the properties or intrinsic marks of a true idea.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A true idea for Spinoza is detailed further in ‘On the Improvement of Understanding’. Spinoza would argue that we can only understand fully an idea that is simply (a circle would be an example it is a simple idea and therefore we only grasp it or do not). From this we can only have a true idea if it is only made up of simple ideas that we understand each simple idea that is made up in the complex idea. The inverse would simply be complex ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;[&amp;hellip;] that fiction cannot be simple, but is made up of the blending of several confused ideas of diverse […] objects or actions existent in nature, or rather is composed of attention directed to all such ideas at once […] and unaccompanied by any mental assent. Now a fiction that was simple would be clear and distinct, and therefore true,&amp;rsquo; (Spinoza, 13-14, 1661).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also derives the definition of a true idea and therefore we understand adequate causes, but also inadequate causes must simply be then, a cause that we do not comprehend. To show the connection to Endeavour to Adequate and Inadequate causes is to show that this are all connected to God. This is done in three ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As God is the infinite substance nothing can exist outside God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because all things are within nature (God) then its apparent that all cause must come from God besides God itself which is its own cause (1PXVICIII).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since all causes derive from God so too does Adequate and Inadequate causes and therefore Adequate causes must be the understanding of god as god is the greatest virtue that we can understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it has been established the account of Endeavour and that adequate causes and inadequate causes since coming from the first cause (God) then it must be that both of these causes must be the reason we understand or not understand God and therefore we understand our Endeavouring more. Even though all Being Endeavour to exist (3PVI) it’s also the case that we can not understand our Endeavouring. Endeavouring then can only be understood because of Adequate causes. To demonstrate this we should look at the idea of an ant, the ant is not conscious and therefore is unaware of its endeavouring it simply does endeavour. We must then look at the effect of both Adequate and Inadequate causes and how they relate to Emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Spinoza, the body and mind, while the same Substance, exist with different modes. The former being the mode of extension and the latter being the mode of thought. (2PVII) this is important because the body is then connected to the external world and the mind the internal. ‘The mind, both in so far as it has clear and distinct ideas, and also in so far as it has confused ideas, endeavours to persist in its being for an indefinite period, and of this endeavour it is conscious.’ (3PIX). The proposition goes on to dictate that when we endeavour with the mind it is our will (which again is not free will as it comes from causes that stem back to God) and when we endeavour with our body its name is appetite. Adequate and Inadequate causes come into play because these causes are via the body as they effect the mind (The causes of emotions are external and then their effects Internal). Adequate increase the power of the mind and Inadequate causes decrease the power of the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘We thus see that the mind can suffer great changes, and can pass now to a greater and now to a lesser perfection […] by joy […] I shall understand the passion by which the mind passes to a greater perfection; by sorrow, on the other hand, the passion by which it passes to a less perfection […] Joy, sorrow, and desire – I know of no other primary affect, the others springing from these’ (3PXIS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the primary Emotions (or Passions) it is clear that external things can then affect the perfection of the internal mind. The relation between these emotions and understanding them will have to be understood by their causes. These are Adequate and Inadequate cause, if you understand Sorrow and its causes then while it will still decrease your perfection it will be limited as it will be an adequate cause from said Sorrow. This all relates back to Endeavouring, the mind picks up on causes from emotions, understands them, and then can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase your perfection and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a greater endeavouring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it as an example, everyone can walk, but depending on your knowledge of how to walk (such as a toddler) it will be easier or harder. This same logic can be applied to emotions. Through knowing the cause of the emotions you’re able to understand them clearer and from that understand the external world better which all relates back to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endeavouring feeds into itself, you understand life itself through adequate and inadequate causes and then emotions (or passions) are then the bridge between the mode of thought and mode of expansion (they also act as a bridge to the external world). There is something to consider however and this is the idea of the ego. Ego is simply the ‘I’ or the ‘self’. When Spinoza talks of the principal condition of Endeavouring, he speaks of ‘But, on the contrary, it is opposed to everything which can negate its existence’ (3PVI). with this and that would be ‘Ego death’ often times induced with psychedelics the feeling of your ego evaporating to a point where you do not have an ego as such. If this can occur, then how does it fit into Spinoza framework? As you cannot endeavour if you do not think you’re a being in-itself (3PVI) it could easily be argued that the source was external (the drug) and thus still fits in, however it would be bettered argued that even though the source is external the results are the same and it is different from death (as that is the end of endeavouring).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spinoza’s account of endeavour is related to Inadequate cause and adequate causes that relate to your emotions as there are connected to the external world which we must understand through the body and understand them as adequate. This has been shown by giving a detailed look at each element and how they then interacted to be a part of Spinoza’s philosophy, however while Spinoza is a wellrespected philosopher it does seem there’s some problems that Spinoza failed to account for either because it didn’t exist at the time or was outside the aims of his philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deductive Argument For Communism</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/deductive_argument_for_communism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/deductive_argument_for_communism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Premise 1: We ought to pursue states of human flourishing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Premise 2: Communism would evoke a state of human flourishing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: Therefore we should pursue Communism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(A=A\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simple argument is a reliable tool in a Communists toolbox. It&amp;rsquo;s premises are basic, only one of which is usually disputed and it serves as a good oppurtunity to discuss communist theory. The most basic line of argument in favour of it is that it would end the domination of capital over man (cf Capital and other of Marx&amp;rsquo;s books on political economy). Which according to Marx is one of the main forms of Capital&amp;rsquo;s alienating power over humans, it is quite simple to argue that; as Capital is a totalitising abstraction which has captured the entire globe in it&amp;rsquo;s wake, it restricts human freedom, creativity, coerces us into unethical workplaces and jobs leading to all kinds of political and social conflicts. Communism is according to Marx, a world free from all of this. The alienation and gap between humanity and Nature would be restored (see Marx&amp;rsquo;s writing on soil science and Liebig) and domination of man over man economically would no longer exist. If Communism is indeed possible, we would see unprecedented levels of human development, spiritually, technologically and scietnifically if it was the dominant mode of production.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immanent Critique of the German Character</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/germany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Germany is a stagnant country. Its people are conservative (not in the political sense), backwards, slow, smug, uninformed and lethargic. The french can bring themselves to riot against a government that fucks up too much but the german will just take it, retaliating only by watching unfunny and ineffectual satire on tv, thinking that he is thereby sticking it to his politicians. The german will feel superior to the stupid american meanwhile his country is technologically stuck in the early 2000s. The global public will praise the supposed quality of german engineering, science and technology even though germany has been a second rate player for decades now. Most germans educated in science and technology end up emigrating to other countries that are marginally less shit. Meanwhile he (the german) is utterly unaware of all of this and genuinely believes himself and his country to be, if not superior in the absolute sense, at least better in most respects to the rest of Europe. If the german does realise that his country is flawed, he will, instead of coming to reasonable conclusions, completely give into his innate superstition and fall victim to all sorts of conspiracy theories. Ah yes superstition, there is no better way to illustrate my point than to show just how superstitious the average german is. It should suffice to mention that homeopathic remedies are sold in every pharmacy and most germans seriously believe they work and represent a real alternative to the tyranny of (((big pharma))), of course it would not occur to them to ask &amp;ldquo;who profits from selling these?&amp;rdquo;. Not to mention his eternal fearmongering over &amp;ldquo;radiation&amp;rdquo;. The German is so delusional as to be scared of phones and microwaves. I rest my case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Response to Suicidality</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/a_response_to_suicidality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/a_response_to_suicidality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been recently propositioned to me that suicide is a radically individualist action. I will state
my position quite briefly and succinctly: this concept is one imagined by slow mind, perhaps
even retarded in its development, and reflects a fundamental deficit in the character of its
author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will begin my response with the first excerpt of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suicide is a rare form of true individualism and is a real rejection of the forced seperation of
one from oneself. The person who commits suicide truly asserts themself over their
situation… and makes their actions their own actions against the wishes of family, friends,
boss’s, teacher’s and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am unconvinced by the definition of “individualism” proposed here. To the author, it is not the
exercisement of liberty, the existence of fundamental rights, or the prioritization of oneself over
the whole? No. The “individualism” outlined here entails only disobeying others, without any
elaboration or nuance. Suppose a society in which norms required the use of a toilet and
sanitation for defecation. In this society, the author would in “radically exercising” his
own individualism, not only embarrass himself but run contrary to his own obvious interests.
Such absurdity is the only logical result from a definition of individualism which does not
consider the motivations (did the author even want to defecate on themselves?) or outcomes of
actions; the only factor to be considered is whether an action faces widespread approval or
disapproval. Individualism would be nothing more than a snide contrarianism.
But the following lines is where the author truly overplays their hand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the little time the individual has to himself for many it is dedicated to useless consumption
of media… None of this contributes to the development of the individual into something
greater or otherwise develops them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, it is revealed that all the posturing of “individualism” and the brave “assertion” of suicide is
merely a facade. In truth, the author accidentally admits that they have no conception of the use
of one’s time beyond mindless consumption. Rational observers might point out the many ways
in which the author could develop themselves physically and mentally &amp;ndash; toning their physique,
seeking opportunities of higher education, discovering a new passion, starting a family &amp;ndash; but
such is unthinkable, the idea that others might dedicate their time to pursuits with meaning &amp;ndash;
unbelievable! Were this person given the ability they so desire, to spend all of their time at their
discretion, they would still engage in the same cycles and routines of mindless consumption.
For someone so obviously attempting to be contrarian, this ironically reveals complete and utter conformity. And thus we arrive at the crux of this perspective: to the author, ending one&amp;rsquo;s existence is a more feasible reality than self improvement or discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will conclude in a very blunt manner: it is no coincidence that such a caricature would imagine
suicide as a victory. Because the suicidal man is not one of strength, but one of weakness. A
man who lacks the minimal creativity to imagine a better future for themself and the motivation
to pursue any act of self improvement in attainment of such. Pleasure, to such a man, is not
happiness, but the lack of pain, because such a life knows no such positives. And I suppose it is
inevitable that one who would chase immediate, hedonistic pleasure so thoroughly in life would eventually come to delude themeselves into seeing the finality of such laziness as death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to the rest of us, suicide remains the ultimate act of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suicidality</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/suicide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/suicide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iskra.money/ox-hugo/lesuicide.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DISCLAIMER: The views expressed here do not represent Iskraism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suicide is something that is often portrayed as the cowardly act of an individual who could not withstand the world or of one who simply surrendered to it. It is portrayed as an act of passivity. However I would argue that suicide can be one of the most radical and self asserting acts one can take. The suicidal individual is no more defeated than the disillusioned individual who although unhappy or angry at either the state of the world or their own personal situation persists and stays complicit even in unchanging circumstances like a worker in a factory endlessly performing the same tasks day after day with little gain even though they may suffer abuse from a boss or simply be worn down by the labor itself. Existing in society today for many wears the individual down in a similar but in a more insidious way. Today the Individual is divided into different categories, a student, a laborer, a family member (these are just example, the categories may change from person to person) But there is little room for the Individual itself, It is instead involved in a grotesque theater playing many different roles at once none of which it is prepared for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the little time the individual has to himself for many it is dedicated to useless consumption of media whether that be watching youtube or netflix or playing video games. None of this contributes to the development of the individual into something greater or otherwise develops them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is little room for creativity or the development of anything original. Nor is there much want for creativity and originality by the masses of individuals. For all the talk of a culture war, culture has stayed stagnant for the most part and there is no real counter culture as the counter cultures that did exist have been absorbed by the superculture. The traditional forms of struggle have been exhausted and the people are exhausted. So for the disillusioned individual there are only 3 options, A desperate act of radicalism and rejection which will although dramatic and theatrical will ultimately change nothing (individuals like the Unibomber and Yukio mishima fall into this category), Grudging acceptance is the path most disillusioned people choose, the attitude of “well this sucks but i suppose it&amp;rsquo;s the best we can do or we cant change it” who although unhappy with the world and or their personal state continue to trudge along letting the order with which they so despite stamp on their face, and finally the ones who like the first category of people have chosen to do something radical, however unlike the first category of people there is no pretext or mask of a grand ideological narrative behind their actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suicide is a rare form of true individualism and is a real rejection of the forced seperation of one from oneself. The person who commits suicide truly asserts themself over their situation and fully takes control of it and makes their actions their own actions against the wishes of family, friends, boss’s, teacher’s and others. It is a truly selfish act which is a rare thing in the modern world. The difference between the selfish suicide of the individual and the theatrical suicide of the man who kills himself with the mask of ideological action is that the suicide of the individual is a radical assertion of the self and selfishness. It is not the mark of one who is defeated like the man who, despite his dissatisfaction with his situation or his society, continues to drudge along. It is instead the mark of one who proclaims the victory of himself by rejecting the circumstances which were not imposed by himself nor accepted by him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Crisis of Iskra: A Response to Alex</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/a_crisis_of_iskra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/a_crisis_of_iskra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, an article was published to iskra.money that made me drop what I was doing to
write this. Currently, I’m working on a large piece discussing war, pornography, and
lonlieness but when I read Alex’s article it made me so baffled by its sheer incompetence
that I had to reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex, the point of iskraism is to be thought provoking, funny, and an open forum. Your
piece was neither thought provoking nor funny and it has made me request that the mod
team be more selective in what they publish. I mean seriously, what were you thinking?
You drop acid once and suddenly you know more than any optometrist in history? A key
thing for any thinker to remember is that nothing they will say is original or unknown, if
you can think of it someone else has as well and they have written about it. No one has
ever thought to publish something so dumb as what you did. Think about this, you are the
first person in history to be this stupid and cocky about something so painfully wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you think you were funny? Did you think this injoke would get a chuckle? It didn’t!
No one is laughing! It fucking sucks, it sucking fucks, I would rather have a buffalo take
a diahrrea dump in my ear than read that again. I would rather eat every shit my
grandmother has ever shat in her lifetime and wash it down with hydrochloric acid
followed by a full course of gelatin made of the leftover juices and slosh in a public
BDSM dungeon than ever read that again. You are a disgrace to this community, your
family, your friends, and your ancestors who gave everything to survive and reproduce
just to have you shit all over their legacy by publishing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the crisis at the center of Iskraism: that someone in the world gave this white boy
acid and now he’s going utterly mad, raving about all the revelations his drug induced
stupidity has given him. Why are we platforming this? Is it in the same way a zoo gives a
platform to monkeys smearing blood riddled stool on the windows of their enclosure? I
am beyond baffled that anyone greenlit this! I place a curse on the heads of Alex and
Jacob that they will touch grass yet forever be just out of reach of getting bitches. Fuck.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://iskra.money/ox-hugo/comedian.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Cannot See Volume.</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/you_cannot_see_volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/you_cannot_see_volume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-proposition&#34;&gt;The proposition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is proposed that vision can only directly percieve in 2d. The author is not proposing that humans cannot think in 3d, this would be prepostrous. The basis of this proposition is that vision constrains a 3rd variable(depth) as a function of two others(direction Euler angle), which in an \(R^3\) space would result in a \(R^2\) space, or a surface. Of course given that by virtue of movement, humans can percieve volume. This is simply done by seeing the inequality of multiple surfaces. This paper should be finished now, no one should dispute the validity of this hypothesis because it is obvious. However, Jacob Little has kidnapped my family and therefore I must continue with examples of how this works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assumptions-made&#34;&gt;Assumptions made&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human vision will be modelled as \(g(\alpha, \beta)\), where the angles \(\alpha\) and \(\beta\) are the horizontal and vertical components of eye angle. The function \(g(\alpha, \beta)\) is defined as the distance percieved by the eye by method of stereo vision. The author recognizes that this model is a simplification of human vision into 1 depth aware sensor rather than a stereo vision system, but this simplification does not alter the argument&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject in question does not move. Movement is how humans use perception of surfaces and their relation to those surfaces as a 3d understanding of reality. The author does not propose that humans cannot &amp;ldquo;truly understand 3d&amp;rdquo; because they have not done enough LSD yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject is presumed to have seen these surfaces before, and therefore can understand their nature through their surface nature (&lt;em&gt;Oberflächennatur&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author assumes that humans exist in a \(R^3\) space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As defined in the above section, \(g(\alpha, \beta)\) is defined against
two angles. I will model a space in which the magnitude of either angle
does not exceed \(\frac{\pi}{2}\). In my graphs, I will represent the
angles on two axes because I cannot be assed to do it otherwise. The
conversion from the pitch/yaw Euler Angle to a parametric curve will be
as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(t) = \vec{r} + t\) &amp;lt;cos(α)cos(β), sin(α)cos(β), sin(β)&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, to find the distance we must find the minimum t(if it exists)
for which the resulting vector intersects with any surface. To do this
and visualize the result, a shitty python script written by a 1st year
university student who cannot even fix trivial bugs in a web service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sphere&#34;&gt;Sphere&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this instance, we take \(\vec{r}_0 = &amp;lt;-5,0,0&amp;gt;\). We also take the
sphere to be \(x^2 + y^2 + z^2 = 1\). This gives the following equation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\[((t cos(\alpha)cos(\beta) - 5)^2 + (t sin(\alpha)cos(\beta))^2 + sin^2(\beta))\]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\[25 - 10tcos(\alpha)cos(\beta) + t^2 cos^2(\alpha)cos^2(\beta) + t^2 sin^2(\alpha)cos^2(\beta) + t^2 sin^2(\beta) -1 = 0\]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quadratic equation that is trivial to solve given a computer
program. And that is what the author will do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a chart of what an observer would see looking towards the
origin from \((-5,0,0)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iskra.money/ox-hugo/Figure_1.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 1: A sphere depth map. The X and Y axes are in radians. The scale is adjusted so that the yellow region describes the places where the observer would be unable to see the depth because the vectors do not intersect the sphere. Otherwise, the color indicates vector length to intersection with the sphere. A stationary observer would be able to understand its nature from the surface solely in the scenario that they have already seen spheres before! Otherwise, they will only be aware of slightly less than half of the sphere&amp;amp;rsquo;s total surface.&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;figure-number&#34;&gt;Figure 1: &lt;/span&gt;A sphere depth map. The X and Y axes are in radians. The scale is adjusted so that the yellow region describes the places where the observer would be unable to see the depth because the vectors do not intersect the sphere. Otherwise, the color indicates vector length to intersection with the sphere. A stationary observer would be able to understand its nature from the surface solely in the scenario that they have already seen spheres before! Otherwise, they will only be aware of slightly less than half of the sphere&amp;rsquo;s total surface.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;plane&#34;&gt;Plane&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is even simpler in comparison to the sphere. The plane we will be
analyzing is the \(x=0\) plane. For this we simply solve
\(t cos(\alpha)cos(\beta) - 5 = 0\) for t to get
\(t = \frac{5}{cos(\alpha)cos(\beta)}\). We then examine the depth map:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iskra.money/ox-hugo/Figure_2.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 2: A depth map of a flat plane. The observer will understand its planar nature, but for example will not know what is behind it, or its depth. For this, the observer would have to move and get the difference of multiple surfaces.&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;figure-number&#34;&gt;Figure 2: &lt;/span&gt;A depth map of a flat plane. The observer will understand its planar nature, but for example will not know what is behind it, or its depth. For this, the observer would have to move and get the difference of multiple surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the author is correct. This was never in dispute but I
want to see my family again, Jacob. Those who dispute this may comment
but they will be incorrect and may cope and relish in their folly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuck off Jacob you&amp;rsquo;re not the real Iskra leader I hate you I hope you
choke in your sleep i&amp;rsquo;m gonna put drain cleaner in your coffee tommorow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Iskraism&#39;s Use of A=A</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/on_iskraisms_use_of_aa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/on_iskraisms_use_of_aa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Jacob has rightly pointed out, when Iskraism is presented with the choice between lalangue and matheme we answer &amp;ldquo;both is best&amp;rdquo;. There is no clearer example of this than our ironic usage of \(A=A\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone asks for the meaning of a word, how do we answer? \(A=A\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our usage of \(A=A\) is an example of lalangue par exellence, we can never say exactly what we mean and so instead we choose to say nothing at all because to say \(A=A\) is both blatantly tautological and devoid of informative content (as Hegel says &amp;ldquo;cognition naively reduced to vacuity&amp;rdquo;). However, at the same time when we say \(A=A\) we also mean something very serious. It is in this sense that is also a matheme, an attempt to transmit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be bold and say that within this formula our entire worldview is implicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As readers of Hegel we know that the Absolute is the identity of identity and non-identity &amp;ndash; identity is always involved in that which negates itself &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In order for \(A\) to have a determinate identity there must be a not-\(A\) (a \(B\), a \(C\) etc.) which is opposed to it. In writing the formula \(A=A\) there is now a second \(A\) which has a moment of othering to the first &amp;ndash; allowing \(A\) to refer to itself reflexively. This is what leads Hegel to criticise Schelling, because for him Schelling&amp;rsquo;s notion of the Absolute cannot think identity and difference. He sees it as an empty schema from which this moment of self-othering is missing hence &amp;ldquo;all is one&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the night in which all cows are black&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of thinking about identity is key to the entirety of Hegel&amp;rsquo;s system, I would go as far as saying it is the dialectical method itself. So then why \(A=A\), rather than \(A = \neg A\) or \(A \neq A\)? We choose to say something which is misleading because we want to demonstrate that language itself is misleading, to demonstrate its circularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, as readers of Badiou we know that such a formula follows from the axiom of extensionality contrary to &amp;ldquo;Law of Identity&amp;rdquo; dogma which takes it as something innate to cognition.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iskra&#39;s Choice</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/iskras_choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/iskras_choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iskra.money/ox-hugo/sexuation.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was originally going to be three (or four) different posts, but I realized they were all connected and this was going to work out pretty well. Each section is smaller than the last, forgive me for this but that&amp;rsquo;s just how my point developed. A large part of this is an elucidation of sexual difference for its relevance to Iskraism. The rest is an incomplete explanation of Iskraism&amp;rsquo;s combination of sophistry and philosophy. A lot of Badiou is implicit in this, but I have purposely chose not to cite anything or formally quote any specific text to avoid entering into the discourse of the master or an academic discourse. We are not academic! This is perhaps the discourse of the hysteric, but Lacan&amp;rsquo;s four discourses are pretty much a sham anyways. In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s purposely informal, I use a lot of parentheticals (the most useful punctuation, and yet the most underused. e.e. cummings shows off the power of parentheses the best).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great French psychoanalytic thinker Jacques Lacan is often critcized for being difficult to understand. People exposed to the density of his Ecrits and the ramblings of his seminars have recourse to the accusation of &amp;ldquo;charlatry&amp;rdquo; towards Lacan. I do not seek to redeem Lacan in the eyes of those who do not (or refuse to) understand him, but it is clear Lacan himself did not help his case for those accusing him of obscurity. His &lt;em&gt;mathemes&lt;/em&gt; such as the one above represent a side of Lacan that is painful to work through for those unfamiliar with the mathematical formalism he attempts to reckon with. What&amp;rsquo;s ironic about the &lt;em&gt;mathemes&lt;/em&gt; is that despite their obvious difficulty, Lacan actually first created them for the purpose of teaching others about psychoanalysis. At the most simple, a &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; is a formalization of a psychoanalytic idea or truth into mathematical formulas. Most people write this off as entirely unecessary, claiming that since Lacan has to then explain the formulas in normal language, he would be better off to just explain it without the formulas in order to reduce obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I seek to show is the necessity of such univocal expression that the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; contains along with the typical equivocal expressions of language. Lacan refers to this equivocation through slips of the tongue, jokes, wordplay, and other examples of the joyful mess of language as &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; a french neologism where he just combines the article &lt;em&gt;la&lt;/em&gt; with the french word for language or tongue, &lt;em&gt;langue&lt;/em&gt;. For Lacan, &lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt; is the only way a subject can first even enter into the realm of language. A baby starts out in language by simply babbling and playing around with sounds and repetition. The domain of the symbolic structure then enters and sets rules down for language, grammar and spelling, which enacts a repression of &lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt;. It is the task of the psychoanalyst then, to pay attention to instances of &lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt; for what they say about the unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sexuation&#34;&gt;Sexuation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; above is (perhaps unfortunately) one of the simpler formulas out there. This contains the famous &amp;ldquo;formulas of sexuation&amp;rdquo;: four formulas describing the cut or difference in the two sexes with the great conclusion that &amp;ldquo;there is no sexual relation&amp;rdquo;, there is no one to one correspondence between the two sexes or any notion of &amp;ldquo;you complete me&amp;rdquo; in the sexual relationship. There is only failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These formulas require a basic knowledge of the language of first order logic. When one writes \(\exists X\), the \(\exists\) operator is called the existential quantifier and can be interepreted as saying that &amp;ldquo;there exists atleast one X&amp;rdquo;. The \(\forall\) operator is the universal quantifier and can be read as saying &amp;ldquo;for all X&amp;rdquo;. \(\Phi X\) is a predicate being applied to X. So for Lacan, \(\Phi\) is the phallic function, castration, signifying a lack in the subject. A line over a formula denotes a negation, so \(\overline{\Phi X}\) would mean that X is not predicated, not subject to castration in Lacan&amp;rsquo;s case. \(X\) is the thing being acted on, in these formulas \(X\) is the set of humans to be sexed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The masculine formula on the left is that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(\exists X~\overline{\Phi X} \\
\forall X~\Phi X\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meaning that all men are subject to castration, but there exists at least one man that is not subject to castration. This exception to castration is what makes the set of men universal, a closed set. This exception is the masculine ideal of someone that escapes castration like John Wayne that is necessary to constitute the whole. All men are constituted in relation to the ideal man, and they necessarily always come up short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feminine formula on the right is that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(\overline{\exists X}~\overline{\Phi X} \\
\overline{\forall X}~\Phi X\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning that there is no woman that is not subject to castration, but not-all women are subject to castration. There is therefore no corresponding singular feminine ideal like there is for masculinity. The set of women is open and cannot be universalized. The feminine ideals are split between the demand for one to be both the virgin mother and the sex object at once. This &amp;ldquo;not-all&amp;rdquo; is what keeps women from being universalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What careful readers may notice about these two positions is that logically they in fact say the same thing! The feminine negation of the universal quantifier (the not-all) means the same thing as affirming the existential quantifier (there exists atleast one). Thus the sexual difference of Lacan does not reside (as conservatives would have it) in a contradiction between the two sexes, forever battling it out, but actually in a radical indifference towards each other. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The radical antinomy and antagonism of sexual difference that scholars like to speak of actually resides in the contradictory formulas internal to each position. The masculine exception is logically impossible, and Lacan does not mean to suggest that it actually exists (it does not exist, it insists). The feminine not-all is also contradictory, to say that no one escapes castration, but not-all women are subject to castration seems absurd. If both sides mean the same thing, perhaps the two sexual positions constitute two different reactions to the same castration that they describe, masculine rejecting castration and feminine accepting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two sides of the formulas of sexuation are a good explanation of the two sides of Lacan&amp;rsquo;s works: the precision and univocity inherent to mathematical formalism occupies a distinctly masculine position, whereas his purposeful ramblings, his jokes, and his wordplay are distinctly feminine. The &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; aspires to reach the level of the masculine exception, free from the castration (lack) that language brings with it because one can only ever speak indirectly in language, whereas mathematical formalism allows precision and univocal expression. &lt;em&gt;Lalangue&lt;/em&gt; on the other hand embraces the incompleteness of the feminine set in all its castration and lack of exception. This idea is played out quite well in a book that Barbara Cassin and Alain Badiou did together called &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s No Such Thing as a Sexual Relationship&amp;rdquo;. Badiou offers a reading of Lacan on the side of &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; and masculinity, whereas Cassin praises the feminine side of wordplay and equivocity of &lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One may question how heteronormative this logic of sexuation is, or perhaps one wants to consider how a non-binary person is constituted in relation to these categories of man and woman. Why only two? Just as a very brief defence, I would like to point out that what we are concerned with here is only sex (not in the biological sense, which is a dead end for Lacan) and not gender. There are only two logics here because those are the only two possibilites! Furthermore, man and woman are constituted from the same set \(X\) because to Lacan, they can only be constituted in (non-) relation to each other. A subject can either embrace castration or deny it. Many books and hundreds of essays have been written on this topic, and I just want to talk about what is relevant to my point here&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sophistry-or-philosophy&#34;&gt;Sophistry or Philosophy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassin&amp;rsquo;s praise of &lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt; is to her an embrace of sophistry over philosophy. Praising equivocation and indirectness, Cassin claims that psychoanalysis requires a reading of the unconscious as a work of sophistry, containing all the slips and puns and such of lalangue, in short: the unsconscious has the ability to produce truth only by speaking indirectly, and this is precisely the goal of sophistry too.
In the opening to their book, Badiou and Cassin state that what they are dealing with is
&amp;ldquo;a new confrontation between, or a new distribution of, the masculinity of Plato and the feminity of sophistics&amp;rdquo; because Badiou remains attached to Plato&amp;rsquo;s rejection of sophistry and extolling of philosophy instead as the place for truth&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Insofar as the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; is the ideal of philosophy, Badiou sees its univocity as the only way to express truths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main characteristic of sophistry is its tendency to run into &amp;ldquo;impasses of the real&amp;rdquo;, the equivocation, ambiguity, and slips where language fails to be exact and instead only speaks indirectly. The real is Lacan&amp;rsquo;s word for that which exactly one is speaking about when speaking indirectly. The real is that which &amp;ldquo;resists symbolization&amp;rdquo;, it is the indicernable and the elusive that evades understanding and cannot be expressed in language without missing something. The real is that which is traumatic for the subject and something wholly impossible. Truth, as that which sophistry gets at indirectly and philosophy formalizes in the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt;, is situated in this register of the real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These impasses of the real remain in the category of the equivocal, but Freud&amp;rsquo;s entire project shows how one can move from and equivocal expression to a univocal one. Freud bases his entire theory on equivocal expressions like dreams, slips, and jokes (&lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt;), but what his project enacts is a move from the equivocal expression, to some univocal truth about the unconscious. Lacan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;mathemes&lt;/em&gt; are a similar move from the equivocal to the univocal through formalization of the equivocal. This is why he says that the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; is a formalization of the impasses. Through formalizing the impasses of the real in the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; the  psychoanalyst (mathematician) can approach truth in this domain of the real. Slavoj Zizek lays out this method of getting at the real with the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; by claiming that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;for Lacan, the Real can only be demonstrated through formal logic, not in a direct way, but negatively, through a deadlock of logical formalization: the Real can only be discerned in the guise of a gap, an antagonism. The primordial status of the Real is that of an obstacle, the absent cause of a failure, a cause which has no positive ontological consistency in itself but is present only through and in its effects. To put it succinctly: one tries to formalize the Real, one fails, and the real &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; this failure. This is why, in the Lacanian Real, opposites coincide: the Real is simultaneously what cannot be symbolized &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the very obstacle which prevents this symbolization. And this coincidence, the coincidence of a Thing with the very obstacle which prevents our access to is, in other words this overlapping of epistemological failure and ontological impossibility, is profoundly Hegelian.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; remains faithful to the old Hegelian dialectical form of seeing how the way in which something fails is also what&amp;rsquo;s necessary and constituitive of the thing. The &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; fails, but this failure of the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; to really talk about the real (since the real is always that which resists symbolization and cannot be expressed) &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; actually the real! Therefore the real as expressed in the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; is not something to be known or not-known, it transcends such categories and instead falls under what Lacan conceives as something to be &amp;ldquo;demonstrated&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;transmitted&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iskra-s-choice&#34;&gt;Iskra&amp;rsquo;s Choice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, the ethics and the practice of Iskraism can be made clear. Our answer to the question of &amp;ldquo;Sophistry or Philsophy?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;man or woman&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt;?&amp;rdquo; is that both is best, and the practice of Iskraism is proof of this! All our jokes, copypastas, and ramblings (babblings) are examples of &lt;em&gt;lalangue&lt;/em&gt;, the attempt to speak indirectly about the real of Iskra. Clearly we see the potential here for a distinctly feminine enjoyment in the joyful mess of language, but there is a masculine side here too. All the math talk, all the philosophy talk, and the entirety of Iskra dot Money serious posts are an attempt at formalizing the real. Though we have not yet gotten to the level of the &lt;em&gt;matheme&lt;/em&gt; (we have made attempts but more to come!), I am still here enacting a project of formalization. But lets be clear: I am still trying to be funny! Iskra dot Money is itself just a bit (that I had to pay for), and it is absolutely absurd that we take it seriously. But this seriousness is a good example of what potential we have in formalization. Formalization can still be funny because of the absurdity of it. So what Iskraism enacts is a project of sexual difference, forever split between (feminine) schizo ramblings and (masculine) comedic formalizations. It seems obvious that you need both in order to both be funny and talk about something real&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are big funny guys, big smart guys, and big schizo guys. Iskra dot Money is absolutely absurd, and I really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t share this with other people because they don&amp;rsquo;t really know what&amp;rsquo;s going on. What is Iskraism? Who is Luka? What is an Iskra? What ramblings are you talking about? Why are you talking about this like it&amp;rsquo;s common knowledge? The history of Iskraism remains a secret to those uninitiated. But lets be clear: this is all a bit. It&amp;rsquo;s all one big bit, that nobody really gets because it&amp;rsquo;s not funny. We do this to be funny but we don&amp;rsquo;t even get it because all we can do is evoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on the radical potential of indifference in the sexual relation see Javier Rivera&amp;rsquo;s piece: &lt;a href=&#34;https://javierrivera-96889.medium.com/love-as-indifference-967da6ff935e&#34;&gt;Love as Indifference.&lt;/a&gt; Those who know me well enough may guess I am venturing into territory I don&amp;rsquo;t feel qualified to speak on (joke).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alenka Zupancic&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;What is Sex?&amp;rdquo; and Joan Copjec&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Imagine There&amp;rsquo;s No Woman&amp;rdquo; are the two most authoritative works in this department.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though for Badiou it is much more complicated than that. His opus, Being and Event, enacts a dethroning of philosophy, taking it down from the position of the &amp;ldquo;love of truth&amp;rdquo; to merely the &amp;ldquo;care of truth&amp;rdquo;. For Badiou, philosophy itself can produce no truth. Truth instead can only come from one of the four conditions of philosophy: politics, love, art, and science. This goes hand in hand with Badiou&amp;rsquo;s famous thesis that mathemtatics = ontology, insofar as ontology is the study of being (qua being). More on this in the coming months, Iskraism is far too deep in Badiou at the moment to speak any further.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what the renegade Luka, who thus far has only proven to be a firebrand revisionist in the face of Iskraism, misses in his stupid Medium posts. He is far too serious. Lets remind ourselves that this guy posts about Rosa Luxemburg&amp;rsquo;s kinks on twitter (and far more unspeakable things on Iskraism) but he wants to write serious posts on Medium. The invite to Iskra dot Money will forever be open to Luka because he is missing out on the ability to do something far better, far more interesting, and far more theoretical (and far more funny).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Struggles in the British Isles</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/political-struggles-in-the-british-isles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/political-struggles-in-the-british-isles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;be me &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;16:00 wake up in my flat above georgian era pub  &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;16:03 go downstairs for a drink &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;ask The Major (my landlord, bartender and employer) why the pub is so quiet &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;he informs me that the pub has been sold &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;the doorway implodes &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;we are immediately hit by an enormous wrecking ball operated by a drunk polish man &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;climb out of the rubble  &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;first time outside the pub for seven years &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;notice a sign put up by a chinese development company &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;we are turning your pub into an ugly block of apartments that looks like a penis&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;16:07 spend my last fiver on half a sandwich from pret &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;decide to kill myself &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;will jump off the tower of london &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;tallest building in the UK, has 3 floors &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;pass 9 more prets on the way to the station &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;16:10 arrive at station &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;its closed &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;16:11 shoved at gunpoint onto rail replacement bus by BTP officer &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;02:13 rail replacement bus arrives at the tower  &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;the apartment complex back home is now finished and owned by saudi property investors &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;02:16 i join the queue for the British Suicide Platform &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;10:30 halfway through the queue &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;ancient yeoman guard asks for my NHS covid QR code &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;explain to him that its buried under a giant penis &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;he immediately sentences me to death &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;i smile as i now get to skip the queue and have someone else throw me off the tower &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;i fall only 2 floors worth of height &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;fall broken by enormous pile of bodies &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;severely injured &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;10:42 go to A&amp;amp;E &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;04:17 leave A&amp;amp;E after being told by unpaid 17 year old indian practitioner to walk it off &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;consider getting a job &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;grumble to myself about having no skills or talents and being lazy &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;street surveillance microphones hear me &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;immediately stuffed into a van with a bag on my head &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;the bag is taken off &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;sadiq khan is standing in front of me &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;he offers me a job at TfL &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;i object to this, saying that no matter how much he pays me i wont work for him &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;i realise my error but it is too late &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;then you&amp;rsquo;re already basically a TfL employee&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;my fate is sealed &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;04:25 i get out of the seat i was put in &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;sadiq sees this and decides im overqualified to be a tube driver &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;be made head of TfL &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;be personally given TfL&amp;rsquo;s debt &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;not able or legally allowed to die until i pay it off &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;ask sadiq why TfL is so poor &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;its cos of the elizabeth line&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;also we keep missing our government quota for suicide bodies on the tracks because of the strikes and closures&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;he asks if i want to stop spending 1 trillion pounds weekly on building the elizabeth line &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;decide to continue building the line, but have it serve as a mass grave &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;05:01 move the pile from the tower of london to the elizabeth line tunnels &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;hit the quota by technicality &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;immediately quit my job &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;05:16 i jump off the tower of london &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;07:48 public rail stations across the country build statues in my memory for fixing TfL &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;09:20 rishi sunak seizes power in a coup &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;brings back franchising and tears down my statues in deborisization &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racism, Classism, and Transhumanism Explored Through the Lens of the Cars Cinematic Universe</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/cars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/cars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear reader, today I pose a simple question: Does racism exist in the Cars universe?
Everything about Cars, their fundamental appearance, is replaceable. Under this pretext, what
‘real’ defining features even exist? How could a racist car distinguish themselves from the
perceived ‘lessers,’ and upon which features could the lines of race ever be drawn? As medical
technology advances, we as a society begin our approach to the same transhumanist,
trans-car-manist, if you would, state of being. We will eventually be forced to consider the same
dilemma that has inevitably become central to the Cars universe, and arrive at the same fork in
the road they undoubtedly have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did the cars navigate their way to a state of enlightenment, eventually diverging from their petty
differences, using the newfound replaceability of their parts as an opportunity to cast the
concept of race aside? Or do they continue to drive themselves insane, frantically searching for
increasingly artificial aspects of identity upon which to divide themselves in a world where
everything becomes interchangeable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose to explore the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the Cars universe, at a time before new paint jobs and rims, rearview mirror-ed our
own – Where unchangeable differences forced them into traditional structures, a race track
comparable to our church. These institutions were oppressive, yes, but where else were the
cars to go? The blue paints’ blood feud with the reds ran deep, and to leave one’s own paint
was certainly suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But oppressive they were nonetheless, and so, through the grace of modernity, one by one they
fell; the walls dividing the cars buckled beneath their own tyranny and for a time, celebrations
were abound. The invention of the spray can was heralded as the end of car-on-car crashes,
the end of hardship, the end of discrimination itself. But it was not meant to be, for the Cars
made a fatal error. Despite all their modern wonders, time eventually proved the radical car
purists right. Because despite all of modernity’s arrogance, there was yet still a single car part
that was truly irreplaceable, unchangeable, untouchable by any invention or workshop: greed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burying their windshields in the sand, the cars were oblivious to the formation of a new
oppressive hierarchy: Capital. The demand for new paints and windshields initially did much to
lessen the differences between the cars, but soon turned devious. If there is no difference, there
is no outlet for greed, no way to express one’s superiority. And so, the car economy rapidly
shifted objectives from the diminishing of differences to the exaggeration of such, solidifying into a new caste system of the rich. and the poor, the Lamborghinis and the corolloas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once every piece of one’s being became for sale, the already intertwined issues of race-ism and
chasse-ism became one. There were no races anymore, but only for the right price – the rich
cars bought their way out of discrimination with whiter paint, and even out of shame with longer
tailpipes and tighter frames. The poor, meanwhile, remain relegated to a state of abject
squander, constantly sold ‘new’ frames and colors that are sure to end their sorrow, all the while
enabling Capital’s creation of new differences through a new beast of carsumerism. And thus,
the cars live their days out in an oppressive dystopia of their own making, where imperfections
are only for the poor and the only god is the very concept of materialistic accumulation itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a U-Turn from the so-called ‘enlightenment’! Modernity’s assumption was that car greed
and selfishness could be satiated by technological advancement, however, these developments
only revealed their true character. By their innate natures, each cage that was broken
necessitated the creation of ten more, a terrible hydra of societal imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what arrogance it would be to see us as any different. Do you think, Mr. Phillips&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, with all
your MIT education, that we are above such mistakes, such foolishness for the sake of greed?
No! All cars will brake before her eternal majesty, all humans will bow before his forever
holiness, beneath the one undeniable commonality between us and the machines we might like to think of ourselves as above: the almighty dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Phillips was the kind gentleman from the MIT alumni organization who interviewed me for their admissions process.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Julie Mehretu</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/mehretu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/mehretu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Julie Mehretu&amp;rsquo;s survey exhibition came to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://high.org/exhibition/julie-mehretu/&#34;&gt;High Museum of Art&lt;/a&gt; last year, I got the chance to see the whole history of her work in the scale it was meant to be viewed. Her pieces are massive, often taking up entire walls, and there is always so much going on in a Mehretu piece. I went to the exhibit twice in one week just because of how much I liked it. Often, art like this is dismissed as obscure or not really saying much, but there&amp;rsquo;s something truly radical at work in her art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mehretu&amp;rsquo;s art is best understood as simply an excercise in abstraction. Her pieces layer intricate images of social space such as architectural blueprints, migration patters, or maps onto large canvases. She displays the abstract, formal social relations in a way that focuses on the spacial over the temporal. Mehretu will often show the whole development of a certain space, layering images from the past on top of one another to display the whole history of something, condensing a multiplicity of temporality into one space that can grasp the multiplicity as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its most basic, Mehretu&amp;rsquo;s art functions much in the same way that Anna Kornbluh claims the realist novel does.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Both function as a project of mapping the world through form, and thereby imagining new possibilites for sociality. Again, her art demands us to think about sociality in terms of space. It enables questions like &amp;ldquo;how does the organzing of space affect the ways in which we interact with the world and groud our collectivity?&amp;rdquo; to be considered by modeling the forms of sociality such as buildings and cities and imagining new forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implicit in all this are conceptions of space that come from architectural criticism. Architecture in Mehretu&amp;rsquo;s art gets at the radical notion of space as constituitive of political struggle. For Fredric Jameson, space is the &amp;ldquo;fundamental category for politics&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and therefore architecture provides a radical political creativity to imagine new ways of organizing social space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This utopian potential in emphasizing the spacial over the temporal elaborated by Jameson starts by representing existing forms of sociality. Stadia II is perhaps the greatest example of the project of social modeling that Mehretu enacts. Stadia II is firstly a work of multiplicity. It is not just a single stadium, but instead a collection of stadia. Banners and flags are all imposed on one another, fans in the stands are interspersed seemingly at random in the background, and wisps of smoke are scattered throughout the piece. Here there seems to be multiple social spaces on display. Stadia II takes insights from set theory&amp;rsquo;s ability to fathom infinitely seperable multiplicity to elaborate the infinitely seperable manifold relations that exist in social space. In mathematics, all objects (functions, numbers, points, lines, etc.) are composed of sets of numbers. There are an infinite amount of these sets, infinitely seperable until we get to the empty set: that subset of every set which contains nothing. This void implicit in every set actually enables mathematics to function. Much in the same way, Mehretu shows here the infinite multiplicity of stadia decomposed and elevated to the level of abstraction. We can decompose social space until all that is left is pure abstraction, the purely formal relations of sociality on display in Stadia II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Stadia II demands is an imagining of social relations that recognizes the necessity of social excess. Public events that take place in a stadium, whether a gladiator fight of the Roman Empire or a contemporary sports game, are all examples of social excess that must come with every composition of social reality. This work shows such excess with the multiplity of lines and wisps of smoke, the inherent chaos implicit in sociality. The mathematical term for such excess is precisely the empty set, that void necessary for the world of mathematics to work. Stadia II elaborates the necessity for such surplus in our conceiving of new forms of social space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great lesson of Mehretu is that art provides a way out of the typical disoriented state of the postmodern subject. Jameson defines our state as &amp;ldquo;the incapacity of our minds, at least as present, to map the great multinational and decentered communicational network in which we find ourselves caught.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Her art does precisely this! Mehretu maps this disoriented network of space by layering intricate images of the forms of social space. Mehretu enacts a project of mapping the formality of social space and representing the large web of relationality that Jameson claims disorients the postmodern subject so wildly. Her art is what Jameson deems a &amp;ldquo;cognitive map&amp;rdquo;: that which &amp;ldquo;instructs about the true economic and social forms of existence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The cognitive maps of Mehretu enable a project of world building that takes into account this inherent chaos of postmodernity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mehretu&amp;rsquo;s choice to abstract reality into the forms that compose sociality defines a radical conception of what art can do. Art allows for entirely new forms of sociality that were previously unthinkable to arise. This grounding for new possibilites is what is so crucial to Alain Badiou&amp;rsquo;s philosophy, what he calls an event: &amp;ldquo;something that brings to light a possibility that was invisible or unthinkable;  it is the creation of a possibility, it opens up a possibility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  This is the same creative power that architecture has, the power to create a new possibile configuration of space. Mehretu herself defines abstraction as &amp;ldquo;a space of possibility&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; , hinting at how the multiplicity of spacial forms that her art models allows for the prospects of imagining new social space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of each episode of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/whytheory&#34;&gt;Why Theory?&lt;/a&gt; podcast, they like to do a &amp;ldquo;lesson of the day&amp;rdquo; where they provide a recommendation or two for further reading or watching on the topic of discussion. I want to do the same here because of how rich and important this topic is. Firstly, everyone should read Anna Kornbluh&amp;rsquo;s book, The Order of Forms. A lot of my analysis relies heavily on her insights into the realist novel and its architectural and mathematical method. Alain Badiou&amp;rsquo;s formalist reading of set theory is amazing to anyone not aquainted with the radicality of mathematics. Perhaps the lesson should be to pay attention in math class. If you should ever have the opportunity to see Julie Mehretu&amp;rsquo;s art in a museum, please make an effort to do so. It will change your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See Anna Kornbluh, &lt;em&gt;The Order of Forms&lt;/em&gt; (Chicago: The University of Chicago Press, 2019)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fredric Jameson, in &lt;em&gt;Architecture, Criticism, and Ideology&lt;/em&gt;, (Princeton: Princeton Architectural Press, 1985), 53.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fredric Jameson, &lt;em&gt;Postmodernism, or the Cultural Logic of Late Capitalism&lt;/em&gt; (Durham: Duke University Press, 1992), 84.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ibid, 409.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alain Badiou, &lt;em&gt;Philosophy and the Event&lt;/em&gt; (Cambridge: Polity Press), 9.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/wuYM15Bh8Jw?t=1228&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/wuYM15Bh8Jw?t=1228&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fetishism and Relations of Domination and Servitude</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/fetishism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/fetishism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[…] one man is king only because other men stand in relation of subjects to him. They, on the contrary imagine that they are subjects because he is king. (Capital Vol 1)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commodity fetish seperates capitalism from other modes of production in so far as social relations are for the first time mediated through things, rather than people. In prior modes of production and governance such as autocracy, rulership was mandated through the divine right of kings - the myth of a blessing from a higher power. A kings mandate is only valid in so far as the people uphold it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commodity circulation requires that both parties are able to “freely” meet on a market - each motivated by their own self interest. The particular content of the commodity exchange is irrelevant, and that both parties must be able to “freely” meet is just a precondition. The actual form is what is important, and it is through the relation between these commodities where belief and ideology actually operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Zizek, the fact that the commodity fetish allows for cynical distance on the part of both the capitalist and the consumer is what makes it so effective. It is not that just there is a false consciousness operating at the level of the commodity exchange, it is actually precisely because the agents are aware of what they are doing - and are able to seperate themselves from it that they can be effective. A truly effective banker is able to accept very well that money is just a social symbol that we ourselves give meaning and so forth but nonetheless by allowing himself to recognise this fact he can do his job most effectively, free from guilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about the counterargument? Is this not the same for relations of domination and servitude? It is certainly true that cynical ideology operated before capitalism, hence Lacan’s point that “The madman is not only a beggar who thinks he is a king, but also a king who thinks he is a king.”. But what really ought to be emphasised here is the material relations behind the layer of ideology (this is not to say that ideology is just false consciousness). The commodity fetish is reified - social behaviour manifests first through the commodity form and relations between things become a form of social domination in a way differing to traditional lordship and bondage. The fact that the commodity form functions regardless of what is said indicates that there is an active element to belief. Belief is constituted through social behaviour, the cynical phantasmic element of ideology cannot function without the real of the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melancholia</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/melancholia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/melancholia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One has to know. One has to know it. One has to have knowledge. Now, to know is to know who and where, to know whose body it really is and what place it occupies—for it must stay in its place. In a safe place. Hamlet does not ask merely to whom the skull belonged (“Whose was it?” the question that Valéry quotes). He demands to know to whom the grave belongs (“Whose grave’s this, sir?”). Nothing could be worse, for the work of mourning, than confusion or doubt: one has to know who is buried where—and it is necessary (to know—to make certain) that, in what remains of him, he remain there. Let him stay there and move no more! (Derrida, Specters of Marx).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From our standpoint of the 21st century, the history of the Left seems to be a history of loss. Each subsequent failure of the left, from the failed revolutions in Eastern Europe to the triumph of liberalism in former communist countries, culminates in the fall of the Berlin Wall in 1989 and subsequent collapse of the Soviet Union. The 20th century failure signifies a certain death of traditional marxist communism that we must wrestle with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that Derrida chose to write his great political work, Specters of Marx, only after the fall of the Berlin Wall. He is concerned with ghosts in this work. Marx haunts us after his death, and we cannot seem to get rid of him despite the academy&amp;rsquo;s zealous attempts to do so. The problems of Capitalism are still apparent to us leftists, and as such we are still indebted to Marx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derrida&amp;rsquo;s work offers a starting point for discourse on how best to interact with Marx after his death, but like all critical theory, Derrida fails to offer a serious solution to the problems he raises, that of the specters of Marx, the points at which capitalism comes up short and Marx&amp;rsquo;s critique shines through.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; His intervention into the world of politics demands us to think about such specters ourselves.i&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derrida relates the current academic relationship with the specters of Marx to Freud&amp;rsquo;s idea of mourning that he develops in Mourning and Melancholia. To Freud, mourning is the simple reaction to the death of a loved person. One may go through a period of depression, or lose interest in the outside world, but the psyche eventually comes to a position that it must abandon its investment in the lost object. But the radical idea in Freud&amp;rsquo;s paper lies in his discussion of melancholia. Melancholia is a relationship to loss very similar to that of mourning, but what is distinctinve about melancholia is its prolonged effects. The melancholic continues to mourn due to some fidelity towards the lost object. But to Freud, it is not all bad for the melancholic. Freud notes that the melancholic subject has &amp;ldquo;a keener eye for the truth&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; than the subject in mourning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heartbreak seems to be the most common example of the radicality of melancholia. As Mari Ruti says, in a heartbreak &amp;ndash; especially one that occurs abruptly &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;we know the identity of the person we have lost, but not the details of the future we could have had with that person.&amp;rdquo; As a result, we stay invested in this lost object, &amp;ldquo;for the melancholic &amp;hellip; even a sad recollection of the lost object is beter than the irrevocable loss that would ensure from replacing that recollection by &amp;hellip; a new object of desire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Perhaps the death of Marx represents the great heartbreak for the left of the 20th century. The great implicit lesson of Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Specters of Marx is that the left must abandon its position of mourning towards Marx and instead embrace the radical ethics of melancholia. We must stay faithful to this &amp;ldquo;sad recollection&amp;rdquo; of Marx in order to imagine a new 21st century form of communism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the true problem for a new leftism is not, as Zizek says,&lt;a href=&#34;https://thephilosophicalsalon.com/can-one-be-a-hegelian-today&#34;&gt;can one be a Hegelian today&lt;/a&gt;, but can one be a Marxist today? It is tempting to focus on where Marx comes up short. The Marxist conception of history remain&amp;rsquo;s caught in a confused notion of incremental progress, Marx has a very limited conception of the state, Marxist politics has an affinity with an eschatological conception of communism as an &amp;ldquo;end of history&amp;rdquo;, he is not without failures. Indeed, the position of the melancholic involves a sort of ambivalence towards the lost object. We love marx, but we also recognize his faults. In Freud&amp;rsquo;s dealings with melancholics, he noted that they are often very critical of themselves, but they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to show any sort of shame. In Freud&amp;rsquo;s view however, such criticisms instead apply towards the lost object, &amp;ldquo;the self-reproaches are reproaches against a loved object which have been shifted away from it on to the patient&amp;rsquo;s own ego.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In this way, the left&amp;rsquo;s criticism towards Marx ought to be self-criticism. We are no longer above Marx. His problems are our problems insofar as Marx is the foundation for any leftist thought, implicitly or explicitly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the question of can one be a Marxist today, the psychoanalytic answer is that one can be a Marxist today with the notion of repetition compulsion: that repetitive drive we have to desire the things that hurt us. The emergence of the New requires the mechanics of repeating Marx, not the same Marx of the past, but a new Marx at a higher level. We here arrive at the idea of repetition that Deleuze comes to as the mechanism for which the New emerges from the Old coming back to haunt us. A truly authentic New is nothing more than a radical repetition of the old. The way we come to understand the New is such that &amp;ldquo;the minimal definition of the New is as an Old which gets stuck and thereby refuses to pass away.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The new Marx must emerge out of the melancholic act of holding onto a stuck Marx. &amp;ldquo;Enter the ghost, exit the ghost, re-enter the ghost&amp;rdquo; as Derrida remarks about Hamlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A truly 21st century Marx must not stand on his own, however. That old intellectual triad of Hegel, Marx, and Psychoanalysis is crucial still.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; When we repeat Marx today, we must understand that he is &amp;ldquo;standing on the shoulders of giants.&amp;rdquo; No investigation into the logic of capital is complete without a rigorous reading of the Hegelian system implicit in Marx&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, a new Marx must extend outside of the world of theory. Marx&amp;rsquo;s insights extend into the world of practice. To repeat Marx is not to simply &amp;ldquo;learn from the failures of the 20th century and do better&amp;rdquo;, but to fail again. Marx himself grasped that great idiom that &amp;ldquo;to act is to err&amp;rdquo;. One must expect to fail because failure is exactly what creates the space for new possibilites. We are speaking here of the logic of Hegel&amp;rsquo;s notion of retroactivity from which an act creates its own ground. In history, the impossible is done all the time. It is just that the act retroactively creates the necessary notions of causality to make it seem possible the whole time. The great Marxist act is precisely this. To fail, and thereby create a new form of success. This is exactly the form that the October Revolution took. It was only through Lenin&amp;rsquo;s failure that his success was possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repetition offers a way out for the melancholic, but one must nonetheless, as Lacan says, &amp;ldquo;traverse the fantasy&amp;rdquo; of melancholia to understand Marx in the 21st century. The crucial lesson of traversing the fantasy is precisely that there is nothing behind this phantasmal marx. There is no other option. In short, the logic of capital that Marx exposes is unmatched and fundamental. Our task is to hold on to Marx, and to repeat him as the New.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derrida names a few in particular such as problems with immigration, nuclear proliferation, and trade wars.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sigmund Freud, &lt;em&gt;Mourning and Melancholia&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari Ruti, &lt;em&gt;Penis Envy and Other Bad Feelings&lt;/em&gt;, p.g. 144-145.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sigmund Freud, &lt;em&gt;Mourning and Melancholia&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slavoj Zizek, &lt;em&gt;Less Than Nothing&lt;/em&gt;, p.g. 483.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highly influential work of Slavoj Zizek and others is what I refer to here as perfectly weaving these three intellectual traditions together.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
