<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neo-Iskra</title>
    <link>https://iskra.money/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Neo-Iskra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iskra.money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>One Will to Rule Them All</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/one_will_to_rule_them_all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/one_will_to_rule_them_all/</guid>
      <description>Nick Land, at least in the present day and time, is a controversial figure among philosophy to say the least. He has been totally disowned by his former academic institutions at the University of Warwick, and more recently the New Centre for Research and Practice (caused by unsavory comments regarding members of the Islamic faith in England). His reputation on the internet is slightly different, however. Mostly known as the &amp;ldquo;philosopher who fried his brain on meth&amp;rdquo;, his philosophical work has for the most part seen most of its success within the past decade or so on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s What Happened Around Us</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/its_what_happened_around_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/its_what_happened_around_us/</guid>
      <description>There’s hardly a need for an introduction paragraph. I could post some stock art of a pirate flag and you’d know what spurred this, assuming you haven’t just woken up from a years long coma and resisted the overpowering and righteous urge to hurl yourself through a window. The circus surrounding Johnny “Rape Her Corpse to Make Sure She’s Dead” Depp’s defamation trial aganist Amber Heard has been like asphixiation by helium, its certainly a bad thing no one seems to be handling well but a few people made funny noises because of it so most of us seem fine with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinoza and the Case of Endeavouring</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/spinoza_and_the_case_of_endeavouring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/spinoza_and_the_case_of_endeavouring/</guid>
      <description>Spinoza lays out in part 1 of ‘The Ethics’ that we are of one substance (God/nature) (1DVI). The substance then has infinite attributes, and modes upon which we are created. In this essay it will be shown what the account of endeavour is, how it relates to Adequate and Inadequate causes and finally how emotions play into both Endeavour and cause.
The account of Endeavour for Spinoza beings in Part Three of the Ethics, ‘Each thing, in so far as it is in itself, endeavours to persevere in its being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deductive Argument For Communism</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/deductive_argument_for_communism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/deductive_argument_for_communism/</guid>
      <description>Premise 1: We ought to pursue states of human flourishing
Premise 2: Communism would evoke a state of human flourishing
Conclusion: Therefore we should pursue Communism
\(A=A\)
This simple argument is a reliable tool in a Communists toolbox. It&amp;rsquo;s premises are basic, only one of which is usually disputed and it serves as a good oppurtunity to discuss communist theory. The most basic line of argument in favour of it is that it would end the domination of capital over man (cf Capital and other of Marx&amp;rsquo;s books on political economy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immanent Critique of the German Character</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/germany/</guid>
      <description>Germany is a stagnant country. Its people are conservative (not in the political sense), backwards, slow, smug, uninformed and lethargic. The french can bring themselves to riot against a government that fucks up too much but the german will just take it, retaliating only by watching unfunny and ineffectual satire on tv, thinking that he is thereby sticking it to his politicians. The german will feel superior to the stupid american meanwhile his country is technologically stuck in the early 2000s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Response to Suicidality</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/a_response_to_suicidality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/a_response_to_suicidality/</guid>
      <description>It has been recently propositioned to me that suicide is a radically individualist action. I will state my position quite briefly and succinctly: this concept is one imagined by slow mind, perhaps even retarded in its development, and reflects a fundamental deficit in the character of its author.
I will begin my response with the first excerpt of interest:
Suicide is a rare form of true individualism and is a real rejection of the forced seperation of one from oneself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suicidality</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/suicide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/suicide/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: The views expressed here do not represent Iskraism.
Suicide is something that is often portrayed as the cowardly act of an individual who could not withstand the world or of one who simply surrendered to it. It is portrayed as an act of passivity. However I would argue that suicide can be one of the most radical and self asserting acts one can take. The suicidal individual is no more defeated than the disillusioned individual who although unhappy or angry at either the state of the world or their own personal situation persists and stays complicit even in unchanging circumstances like a worker in a factory endlessly performing the same tasks day after day with little gain even though they may suffer abuse from a boss or simply be worn down by the labor itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Crisis of Iskra: A Response to Alex</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/a_crisis_of_iskra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/a_crisis_of_iskra/</guid>
      <description>Recently, an article was published to iskra.money that made me drop what I was doing to write this. Currently, I’m working on a large piece discussing war, pornography, and lonlieness but when I read Alex’s article it made me so baffled by its sheer incompetence that I had to reply.
Alex, the point of iskraism is to be thought provoking, funny, and an open forum. Your piece was neither thought provoking nor funny and it has made me request that the mod team be more selective in what they publish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Cannot See Volume.</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/you_cannot_see_volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/you_cannot_see_volume/</guid>
      <description>The proposition It is proposed that vision can only directly percieve in 2d. The author is not proposing that humans cannot think in 3d, this would be prepostrous. The basis of this proposition is that vision constrains a 3rd variable(depth) as a function of two others(direction Euler angle), which in an \(R^3\) space would result in a \(R^2\) space, or a surface. Of course given that by virtue of movement, humans can percieve volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Iskraism&#39;s Use of A=A</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/on_iskraisms_use_of_aa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/on_iskraisms_use_of_aa/</guid>
      <description>As Jacob has rightly pointed out, when Iskraism is presented with the choice between lalangue and matheme we answer &amp;ldquo;both is best&amp;rdquo;. There is no clearer example of this than our ironic usage of \(A=A\).
If someone asks for the meaning of a word, how do we answer? \(A=A\)
Our usage of \(A=A\) is an example of lalangue par exellence, we can never say exactly what we mean and so instead we choose to say nothing at all because to say \(A=A\) is both blatantly tautological and devoid of informative content (as Hegel says &amp;ldquo;cognition naively reduced to vacuity&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iskra&#39;s Choice</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/iskras_choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/iskras_choice/</guid>
      <description>This was originally going to be three (or four) different posts, but I realized they were all connected and this was going to work out pretty well. Each section is smaller than the last, forgive me for this but that&amp;rsquo;s just how my point developed. A large part of this is an elucidation of sexual difference for its relevance to Iskraism. The rest is an incomplete explanation of Iskraism&amp;rsquo;s combination of sophistry and philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Struggles in the British Isles</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/political-struggles-in-the-british-isles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/political-struggles-in-the-british-isles/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;be me &amp;gt;16:00 wake up in my flat above georgian era pub &amp;gt;16:03 go downstairs for a drink &amp;gt;ask The Major (my landlord, bartender and employer) why the pub is so quiet &amp;gt;he informs me that the pub has been sold &amp;gt;the doorway implodes &amp;gt;we are immediately hit by an enormous wrecking ball operated by a drunk polish man &amp;gt;climb out of the rubble &amp;gt;first time outside the pub for seven years &amp;gt;notice a sign put up by a chinese development company &amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;we are turning your pub into an ugly block of apartments that looks like a penis&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;16:07 spend my last fiver on half a sandwich from pret &amp;gt;decide to kill myself &amp;gt;will jump off the tower of london &amp;gt;tallest building in the UK, has 3 floors &amp;gt;pass 9 more prets on the way to the station &amp;gt;16:10 arrive at station &amp;gt;its closed &amp;gt;16:11 shoved at gunpoint onto rail replacement bus by BTP officer &amp;gt;02:13 rail replacement bus arrives at the tower &amp;gt;the apartment complex back home is now finished and owned by saudi property investors &amp;gt;02:16 i join the queue for the British Suicide Platform &amp;gt;10:30 halfway through the queue &amp;gt;ancient yeoman guard asks for my NHS covid QR code &amp;gt;explain to him that its buried under a giant penis &amp;gt;he immediately sentences me to death &amp;gt;i smile as i now get to skip the queue and have someone else throw me off the tower &amp;gt;i fall only 2 floors worth of height &amp;gt;fall broken by enormous pile of bodies &amp;gt;severely injured &amp;gt;10:42 go to A&amp;amp;E &amp;gt;04:17 leave A&amp;amp;E after being told by unpaid 17 year old indian practitioner to walk it off &amp;gt;consider getting a job &amp;gt;grumble to myself about having no skills or talents and being lazy &amp;gt;street surveillance microphones hear me &amp;gt;immediately stuffed into a van with a bag on my head &amp;gt;the bag is taken off &amp;gt;sadiq khan is standing in front of me &amp;gt;he offers me a job at TfL &amp;gt;i object to this, saying that no matter how much he pays me i wont work for him &amp;gt;i realise my error but it is too late &amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;then you&amp;rsquo;re already basically a TfL employee&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;my fate is sealed &amp;gt;04:25 i get out of the seat i was put in &amp;gt;sadiq sees this and decides im overqualified to be a tube driver &amp;gt;be made head of TfL &amp;gt;be personally given TfL&amp;rsquo;s debt &amp;gt;not able or legally allowed to die until i pay it off &amp;gt;ask sadiq why TfL is so poor &amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;its cos of the elizabeth line&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;also we keep missing our government quota for suicide bodies on the tracks because of the strikes and closures&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;he asks if i want to stop spending 1 trillion pounds weekly on building the elizabeth line &amp;gt;decide to continue building the line, but have it serve as a mass grave &amp;gt;05:01 move the pile from the tower of london to the elizabeth line tunnels &amp;gt;hit the quota by technicality &amp;gt;immediately quit my job &amp;gt;05:16 i jump off the tower of london &amp;gt;07:48 public rail stations across the country build statues in my memory for fixing TfL &amp;gt;09:20 rishi sunak seizes power in a coup &amp;gt;brings back franchising and tears down my statues in deborisization </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racism, Classism, and Transhumanism Explored Through the Lens of the Cars Cinematic Universe</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/cars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/cars/</guid>
      <description>Dear reader, today I pose a simple question: Does racism exist in the Cars universe? Everything about Cars, their fundamental appearance, is replaceable. Under this pretext, what ‘real’ defining features even exist? How could a racist car distinguish themselves from the perceived ‘lessers,’ and upon which features could the lines of race ever be drawn? As medical technology advances, we as a society begin our approach to the same transhumanist, trans-car-manist, if you would, state of being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Julie Mehretu</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/mehretu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/mehretu/</guid>
      <description>When Julie Mehretu&amp;rsquo;s survey exhibition came to the High Museum of Art last year, I got the chance to see the whole history of her work in the scale it was meant to be viewed. Her pieces are massive, often taking up entire walls, and there is always so much going on in a Mehretu piece. I went to the exhibit twice in one week just because of how much I liked it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fetishism and Relations of Domination and Servitude</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/fetishism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/fetishism/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;[…] one man is king only because other men stand in relation of subjects to him. They, on the contrary imagine that they are subjects because he is king. (Capital Vol 1)&amp;rdquo;
The commodity fetish seperates capitalism from other modes of production in so far as social relations are for the first time mediated through things, rather than people. In prior modes of production and governance such as autocracy, rulership was mandated through the divine right of kings - the myth of a blessing from a higher power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melancholia</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/melancholia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/melancholia/</guid>
      <description>One has to know. One has to know it. One has to have knowledge. Now, to know is to know who and where, to know whose body it really is and what place it occupies—for it must stay in its place. In a safe place. Hamlet does not ask merely to whom the skull belonged (“Whose was it?” the question that Valéry quotes). He demands to know to whom the grave belongs (“Whose grave’s this, sir?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sports and the Cult of the Body Under Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://iskra.money/posts/bodycult_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iskra.money/posts/bodycult_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>Now that summer season has fully started and the holidays in the Author&amp;rsquo;s country are kicking in, one can observe with increasing frequency the promotion of the &amp;ldquo;Summer Body&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Beach Body&amp;rdquo; everywhere, colorful advertisements for sports products and diet fads litter every magazine near the counter of your favorite grocery store. When going for a walk, one can observe all manners of people going about their daily fitness routines, be it walking, jogging, or even the fashionable &amp;ldquo;Street Workout&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
